[
  { "question": "plašč", "answer": "coat" },
  { "question": "bluza", "answer": "blouse" },
  { "question": "čevlji", "answer": "shoes" },
  { "question": "hlače", "answer": "trousers" },
  { "question": "krilo", "answer": "skirt" },
  { "question": "obleka", "answer": "dress" },
  { "question": "klobuk", "answer": "hat" },
  { "question": "palčnike", "answer": "mittens" },
  { "question": "rokavice", "answer": "gloves" },
  { "question": "majica (s kratkimi rokavi)", "answer": "T-shirt" },
  { "question": "jakna", "answer": "jacket" },
  { "question": "šal", "answer": "scarf" },
  { "question": "kavbojke", "answer": "jeans" },
  { "question": "kapa s šiltom", "answer": "cap" },
  { "question": "pulover", "answer": "pullover" },
  { "question": "žabe / pajkice", "answer": "tights" },
  { "question": "srajca", "answer": "shirt" },
  { "question": "nogavice", "answer": "socks" },
  { "question": "škornji", "answer": "boots" },
  { "question": "ženska torbica", "answer": "handbag" },
  { "question": "kravata", "answer": "tie" },
  { "question": "superge", "answer": "trainers" },
  { "question": "pižama", "answer": "pyjamas" },
  { "question": "kratke hlače", "answer": "shorts" },
  { "question": "copati", "answer": "slippers" },
  { "question": "volnena kapa", "answer": "woollen hat" },
  { "question": "Dani ima srajco in kavbojke na mizi.", "answer": "Dani's shirt and jeans are on the table." },
  { "question": "Njegov pulover leži pod mizo.", "answer": "His pullover is lying under the table." },
  { "question": "Njegove hlače visijo čez stol.", "answer": "His trousers are hanging over the chair." },
  { "question": "Njegova majica je na omari.", "answer": "His T-shirt is on the wardrobe." },
  { "question": "Njegovi škornji so na spodnji polici.", "answer": "His boots are on the bottom shelf." },
  { "question": "Njegove rokavice ležijo na tleh.", "answer": "His gloves are lying on the floor." },
  { "question": "Dani ima nogavice na tleh.", "answer": "Dani's socks are on the floor." },
  { "question": "Tinina kapa, šal, plašč in obleka so na obešalniku.", "answer": "Tina's hat, scarf, coat and dress are on the hanger." },
  { "question": "Njena kapa s šiltom in en palčnik sta na postelji.", "answer": "Her cap and one mitten are on the bed." },
  { "question": "Drugi palčnik je na blazini.", "answer": "The other mitten is on the pillow." },
  { "question": "Majica je na zgornji polici.", "answer": "The T-shirt is on the top shelf." },
  { "question": "Plašč je na obešalniku.", "answer": "The coat is on the hanger." },
  { "question": "Šal je na zgornji polici.", "answer": "The scarf is on the top shelf." },
  { "question": "Kapa je v desnem predalu.", "answer": "The cap is in the right drawer." },
  { "question": "Kavbojke so na obešalniku.", "answer": "The jeans are on the hanger." },
  { "question": "Čevlji so na spodnji polici.", "answer": "The shoes are on the bottom shelf." },
  { "question": "Rokavice so v desnem predalu.", "answer": "The gloves are in the right drawer." },
  { "question": "Nogavice so v levem predalu.", "answer": "The socks are in the left drawer." },
  { "question": "Obuj Billyja: obleci mu majico in pobarvaj jo zeleno.", "answer": "Dress Billy. Put on a T-shirt and colour it green." },
  { "question": "Nato mu obleci kavbojke in jih pobarvaj modro.", "answer": "Next put on jeans and colour them blue." },
  { "question": "Nato mu obleci nogavice in jih pobarvaj rjavo.", "answer": "Then put on socks and colour them brown." },
  { "question": "Nato mu obleci čevlje in jih pobarvaj črno.", "answer": "After that put on shoes and colour them black." },
  { "question": "Na koncu mu daj kapo in jo pobarvaj rdeče.", "answer": "Finally put on a cap and colour it red." },
  { "question": "Koliko stane ta klobuk?", "answer": "How much is this hat?" },
  { "question": "Stane 15 evrov.", "answer": "It's €15 (fifteen)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stane ta bluza?", "answer": "How much is this blouse?" },
  { "question": "Stane 35 evrov.", "answer": "It's €35 (thirty-five)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stanejo te srajce?", "answer": "How much are these shirts?" },
  { "question": "Stanejo 38 evrov.", "answer": "They're €38 (thirty-eight)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stane ta obleka?", "answer": "How much is this dress?" },
  { "question": "Stane 88 evrov.", "answer": "It's €88 (eighty-eight)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stanejo ti čevlji?", "answer": "How much are these shoes?" },
  { "question": "Stanejo 75 evrov.", "answer": "They're €75 (seventy-five)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stane ta pulover?", "answer": "How much is this sweater?" },
  { "question": "Stane 89 evrov.", "answer": "It's €89 (eighty-nine)." },
  { "question": "Koliko stanejo te kavbojke?", "answer": "How much are these jeans?" },
  { "question": "Stanejo 100 evrov.", "answer": "They're €100 (a hundred)." },
  { "question": "Obleka ne naredi človeka.", "answer": "Clothes don't make the man." },
  { "question": "rumeni čevlji", "answer": "yellow shoes" },
  { "question": "modra kapa", "answer": "blue cap" },
  { "question": "rdeča majica", "answer": "red T-shirt" },
  { "question": "črne hlače", "answer": "black trousers" },
  { "question": "zelena obleka", "answer": "green dress" },
  { "question": "rjave nogavice", "answer": "brown socks" },
  { "question": "roza krilo", "answer": "pink skirt" },
  { "question": "oranžen pulover", "answer": "orange sweater" },
  { "question": "trideset", "answer": "thirty" },
  { "question": "štirinajst", "answer": "fourteen" },
  { "question": "petdeset", "answer": "fifty" },
  { "question": "šestdeset", "answer": "sixty" },
  { "question": "šestnajst", "answer": "sixteen" },
  { "question": "petnajst", "answer": "fifteen" },
  { "question": "štirideset", "answer": "forty" },
  { "question": "trinajst", "answer": "thirteen" },
  { "question": "devetdeset", "answer": "ninety" },
  { "question": "osemnajst", "answer": "eighteen" },
  { "question": "sedemnajst", "answer": "seventeen" },
  { "question": "sto", "answer": "a hundred" },
  { "question": "Kaj ima oblečeno Anne?", "answer": "She's wearing a sweater, trousers and mittens." },
  { "question": "Kaj ima oblečeno Helen?", "answer": "She's wearing a sweater, trousers, boots, a scarf and a cap." },
  { "question": "Kaj ima oblečeno David?", "answer": "He's wearing a sweater, trousers and trainers." },
  { "question": "Kaj ima oblečeno Lisa?", "answer": "She's wearing a sweater, a skirt, boots and a scarf." },
  { "question": "Kaj ima oblečeno William?", "answer": "He's wearing a T-shirt, shorts and slippers." },
  { "question": "spalna srajca", "answer": "nightshirt" },
  { "question": "spalna halja", "answer": "nightgown" },
  { "question": "pižama", "answer": "pyjamas" },
  { "question": "copati", "answer": "slippers" },
  { "question": "škornji", "answer": "boots" },
  { "question": "kapa", "answer": "hat" },
  { "question": "šal", "answer": "scarf" },
  { "question": "kapuca", "answer": "hood" },
  { "question": "sandali", "answer": "sandals" },
  { "question": "Operemo jih.", "answer": "We wash them." },
  { "question": "Najprej damo oblačila v toplo vodo in dodamo detergent.", "answer": "First we put the clothes in warm water and add some detergent." },
  { "question": "Nato jih podrgnemo, da se očistijo.", "answer": "Next we rub them with our hands to get them clean." },
  { "question": "Potem jih obesimo na vrv.", "answer": "After that we hang them on the washing line." },
  { "question": "Nato jih zlikamo.", "answer": "Then we iron them." },
  { "question": "Na koncu jih nosimo, ko gremo ven.", "answer": "Finally we wear them when we go out." },
  { "question": "Na deževen dan vzamemo dežnik.", "answer": "We take an umbrella on rainy days." },
  { "question": "Angleški učenci nosijo šolske uniforme.", "answer": "English students wear school uniforms." },
  { "question": "Dani potrebuje nove superge za nogomet.", "answer": "Dani needs new trainers for football." },
  { "question": "Koliko stanejo ti palčniki?", "answer": "How much are these mittens?" },
  { "question": "obutev", "answer": "footwear" },
  { "question": "sandali", "answer": "sandals" },
  { "question": "nogavice", "answer": "socks" },
  { "question": "superge", "answer": "trainers" },
  { "question": "dežnik", "answer": "umbrella" },
  { "question": "dežni plašč", "answer": "raincoat" },
  { "question": "gumijasti škornji", "answer": "rubber boots" },
  { "question": "škornji", "answer": "boots" },
  { "question": "Max želi kupiti novo majico.", "answer": "Max wants to buy a new T-shirt." },
  { "question": "Vstopi v trgovino in poišče majice.", "answer": "He walks into the store and looks for T-shirts." },
  { "question": "Hoče črno majico, zato jo išče.", "answer": "He wants a black T-shirt so he looks for it." },
  { "question": "Ko jo najde, gre v kabino.", "answer": "When he finds it he takes it to the dressing room." },
  { "question": "Pomeri majico. Prav mu je in zelo mu je všeč.", "answer": "He tries the black T-shirt on. It fits him and he likes it very much." },
  { "question": "Sleče jo in gre do blagajne.", "answer": "He takes it off and he goes with it to the cashier." },
  { "question": "Kupi jo in jo odnese domov.", "answer": "He buys it and takes it home." },
  { "question": "Zelo je vesel nove majice.", "answer": "He is very happy with his new T-shirt." },
  { "question": "vas", "answer": "village" },
  { "question": "copati", "answer": "slippers" },
  { "question": "jutro", "answer": "morning" },
  { "question": "hiša", "answer": "house" },
  { "question": "bos", "answer": "barefoot" },
  { "question": "gozd", "answer": "forest" },
  { "question": "čista in popravljena oblačila", "answer": "clean and mended clothes" },
  { "question": "nova oblačila", "answer": "new clothes" },
  { "question": "moja najljubša oblačila so trenirka, majica in superge.", "answer": "My favourite clothes are a tracksuit, a T-shirt and trainers." },
  { "question": "poleti nosim kratke hlače in majico.", "answer": "In summer I wear shorts and a T-shirt." },
  { "question": "pozimi nosim hlače, pulover in plašč.", "answer": "But in winter I wear trousers, a sweater and a coat." },
  { "question": "ko dežuje, oblečem dežni plašč.", "answer": "When it’s rainy I put on a raincoat." },
  { "question": "v šoli ne nosim uniforme.", "answer": "At school I don’t wear a school uniform." },
  { "question": "ko grem spat, oblečem pižamo.", "answer": "When I go to bed I put on my pyjamas." },
  { "question": "doma včasih pospravim sobo.", "answer": "At home I sometimes tidy my room." },
  { "question": "vedno pospravim oblačila v omaro.", "answer": "I always put my clothes in the wardrobe." },
  { "question": "vedno kupim oblačila, ki so mi všeč.", "answer": "I always buy clothes that I like." }
]